So, hello everyone, in this video we are going to work with our components, okay.
So now, before this we are going to install some few packages.
So go into their front and folder and now NPMI React route DOM, we are going to install these
packages in order to work with it.
So hot toast React hot toast and axios for fetching the APIs response and choose stand
for state management, this one React Auto DOM, I guess all you have known for routing
to different pages, this React hot toast is for like sending when you send and receive
messages, we will have this notification write pop up kind of notification which is
which comes in a green or red format.
So for this, so let's install all of this, so now it's getting installed, one more thing
is that we don't need this app.css, okay, so delete this one, okay.
Now what we are going to do is, first let's go to the main.jsx file, okay, higher you can see
the stick mode, now what we are going to do is import, wait, sorry for the noise, import
browser router from React router DOM, okay and go inside this stick mode and we are going
to wrap our app component with this browser router, so browser router, so remove all of this,
close this one, okay, sorry for this actually, okay, now we have saved it, now since we
need different kind of components, right, so go inside the source folder and make one component
folder, so components inside the components, what we are going to do is suppose the first
component, it would be the navbar, right, so navbar, so navbar.jsx, right, so now let's
go inside and make one function navbar equals to, and now return some different component
from the navbar function, so return dev, for example we are going to just say this like
this, okay, so navbar, and now we are going to export default navbar, so control and
S, and for this one what we are going to do is go inside the app.jsx, okay, inside app.jsx
we are going to just import our navbar component, so let's import navbar from components
last navbar, and then what we are going to do is since we are going to use, like route
to different pages, like it would be sign a page login page to file page or home page,
so for this one here we are going to apply our react router down package, we are going
to use our react router down package, so import route, routes from react router down, okay,
control S, save, and now remove this return statement here, after it removing this return
statement, let's for now just return the dev, and after dev, let's take our navbar
component, okay, and after this we are just going to use the routes, and then inside
route, which is a single closing component, so route path equal to suppose we are going
to the home page of our website, so in that case we are going to use just a slash and
equals to suppose for now we have this home page, okay, so home page, so after this
close this one, similarly it would be like control C, control V, paste for different
things like sign a page, we have home page, and then we have this sign up page, then
after that it would be home page sign up page, login page, login page, then after this login
page we would be having profile page, okay, so profile page slash profile, and the element
would be one second profile page, profile page, so all of this we had made, so for all
this home page sign up page, login page, and a profile page in the component, so folder
we are going to make this one by one, so like this navbar kind of only, so let's go and
make this, so it would be home page dot j6, const home page equals to like this export
home page, export default home page, export default home page, okay, and return some component
which is called as div, and suppose we are going to return this h1 for now, and it is home
page, okay, so navbar is done, home page is done, now inside of the ambedo or j6 we have,
sorry, app dot j6 we have sign up page, login page, and profile page, so for all of this we
are going to make this, and also we are forgetting here sign up, and login, and then here
profile, so control as save, let's make for this one, so sign up, so go here, and paste
this, and dot j6, okay, so const, sign up page equals to, and we are going to return a
div with the same thing, so h1 sign up page, I am going to copy paste this in order to save
of the time, okay, so export default sign up page, so copy all of this we are going to make
another component which is called as login, so wrap dot j6 login, control c, and inside
of the components we will have one more file, login page dot j6, go inside the sign
up, control c, login page, control v, this name, this has login, wait, once again, okay,
so I have made all of the pages, so const login page equal to login page, and as you can
see this, and for the profile page also I have made this one component, for sign up page
also I have made this one component, okay, so you can copy of all of these, and in the
app dot j6 I have imported all of these files, like import homepage from the components
slash homepage login page, sign up page, and profile page, and I have used all of them, sorry,
so I have used all of them here, like if this navigates to the homepage, then in that case
homepage would be shown, in case like there is a sign up, like you navigate to the sign
up page, then the sign up page element will be shown, and for the login and profile we are
showing all of the respective component, okay, so that is it, and one thing I would like
to do is, like since this component, like we are putting everything inside of the components
folder, right, but in my case what I will do is, I will make pages folder inside of the
pages folder, I have shipped all of these sign up page profile page, and now I am thinking
to do this, because it would be good only.